A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 2004-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 2004-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.081
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is prohibited for ten years from the date of creation unless special permission is granted by the President's Office. Under the terms of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Sec. 2.1-343 (4), the records of the president or other chief executive officer of any state-supported institution of higher education are exempt from the law's access provisions.
Additional access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred from the Office of the President, Madison Hall, University of Virginia, through Peggy S. Pasternak, on August 14, 2008.
Scope and Content
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia, John Thomas Casteen, III, ca. 7,200 items (24 Hollinger boxes, ca. 10 linear shelf feet), 2005-2006.
The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office. Major topics include American Council on Education; Association of American Universities; athletics and the NCAA; the Council of Presidents of State-Aided Institutions of Higher Learning in Virginia; development; the General Assembly; the Governor of Virginia's office; the Mariners' Museum; the Medical Center and the Health Services Foundation; Reserve Officers' Training Corps; State Council of Higher Education for Virginia; and Student Affairs.
Arrangement
Both the series and file headings used by the president's office have been retained. Restricted material has been placed in its own series. There are two series: Series I) General Files (Boxes 1-20); Series II) Restricted Files (Boxes 21-24).
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - 2005-2006 A-Aq Miscellaneous, (14 items) (Box-folder 1:1)
  - 2005-2006 Ar-Az Miscellaneous, (17 items) (Box-folder 1:2)
  - 2006 African-American Affairs, (2 items) (Box-folder 1:3)
  - 2005-2006 Alumni Association, (13 items) (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 2005-2006 American Council on Education, (11 items) (Box-folder 1:5)
  - 1992-1996 American Council on Education Fellows, (17 items) (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 1998-2000 American Council on Education Fellows, (7 items) (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 2001-2005 American Council on Education Fellows, (10 items) (Box-folder 2:3)
  - 2005 Applications for Positions, (1 item) (Box-folder 2:4)
  - 2005 Architect of the University, Office of, (3 items) (Box-folder 2:5)
  - 2005-2006 Architecture, School of, (13 items) (Box-folder 2:6)
  - 2005 Art, Department of, (1 item) (Box-folder 2:7)
  - 2005-2006 Art Museum, (4 items) (Box-folder 2:8)
  - 2005-2006 Arts and Sciences, (4 items) (Box-folder 2:9)
  - 2004 November-2005 August Association for the Accreditation of Human Research Protection Programs, (28 items) (Box-folder 3:1)
  - 2005 September Association for the Accreditation of Human Research Protection Programs, (28 items) (Box-folder 3:2)
  - 2005 November-2006 March Association for the Accreditation of Human Research Protection Programs, (13 items) (Box-folder 3:3)
  - 2005-2006 Association of American Colleges and Universities, (5 items) (Box-folder 3:4)
  - 2005 Association of American Universities, (10 items) (Box-folder 3:5)
  - 2006 Association of American Universities, (2 items) (Box-folder 4:1)
  - 2005-2006 Association of Governing Boards, (8 items) (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 2005-2006 Athletics, (18 items) (Box-folder 4:3)
  - 2005 Athletics-Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC), (11 items) (Box-folder 4:4)
  - 2006 Athletics-Atlantic Coast Conference, (8 items) (Box-folder 4:5)
  - 2005-2006 Athletics-National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA), (19 items) (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 2005 Auditor of Public Accounts, (11 items) (Box-folder 5:1)
  - 2005-2006 Ba-Be Miscellaneous, (14 items) (Box-folder 5:2)
  - 2005-2006 Bf-Br Miscellaneous, (12 items) (Box-folder 5:3)
  - 2005-2006 Br-Bz Miscellaneous, (8 items) (Box-folder 5:4)
  - 2005 June-2006 February Business and Finance, (25 items) (Box-folder 5:5)
  - 2006 March Business and Finance, (7 items) (Box-folder 5:6)
  - 1006 April-June Business and Finance, (20 items) (Box-folder 5:7)
  - 2005-2006 Ca Miscellaneous-Folder 1 of 2, (4 items) (Box-folder 6:1)
  - 2005-2006 Ca Miscellaneous-Folder 2 of 2, (5 items) (Box-folder 6:2)
  - 2005-2006 Cb-Co Miscellaenous, (17 items) (Box-folder 6:3)
  - 2005-2006 Co Miscellaenous-Folder 1 of 3, (6 items) (Box-folder 6:4)
  - 2005-2006 Co Miscellaneous-Folder 2 of 3, (2 items) (Box-folder 6:5)
  - 2005-2006 Co Miscellaneous-Folder 3 of 3, (6 items) (Box-folder 6:6)
  - 2005 Cp-Cz Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 7:1)
  - 2005-2006 Carr's Hill, (2 items) (Box-folder 7:2)
  - 2000-2005 Casteen, John T. III, (2 items) (Box-folder 7:3)
  - 2005 Cavalier Daily, (1 item) (Box-folder 7:4)
  - 2006 Charlottesville, (3 items) (Box-folder 7:5)
  - 2005-2006 Chesapeake Bay Foundation, (18 items) (Box-folder 7:6)
  - 2006 Commerce, School of, (1 item) (Box-folder 7:7)
  - 2005-2006 Community Relations, (4 items) (Box-folder 7:8)
  - 2005-2006 Condolences-A-K, (24 items) (Box-folder 7:9)
  - 2005-2006 Condolences-L-Z, (30 items) (Box-folder 7:10)
  - 2005-2006 Congress, (6 items) (Box-folder 7:11)
  - 2005-2006 Continuing and Professional Studies, School of, (13 items) (Box-folder 7:12)
  - 2004-2006 Council for Higher Education Accreditation, (7 items) (Box-folder 7:13)
  - 2005 Council of Presidents (Virginia), (10 items) (Box-folder 7:14)
  - 2005-2006 Council of Presidents (Virginia), (7 items) (Box-folder 7:15)
  - 2005-2006 D Miscellaneous, (12 items) (Box-folder 8:1)
  - 2005 Darden, Joshua, (4 items) (Box-folder 8:2)
  - 2005 Darden School, (49 items) (Box-folder 8:3)
  - 2005-2006 Darden School 2, (51 items) (Box-folder 8:4)
  - 2005 November 29 Deans' Development Forum, (21 items) (Box-folder 8:5)
  - 2005 November 29 Deans' Development Forum, (1 item) (Box-folder 8:6)
  - 2005 August 17 Deans' Retreat, (2 items) (Box-folder 9:1)
  - 2005 E Miscellaneous, (3 items) (Box-folder 9:2)
  - 2005-2006 Education School, (13 items) (Box-folder 9:3)
  - 2005 Engineering and Applied Sciences School, (23 items) (Box-folder 9:4)
  - 2006 Engineering and Applied Sciences School, (16 items) (Box-folder 9:5)
  - 2005 English Department, (2 items) (Box-folder 9:6)
  - 2005-2006 Equal Opportunity Programs Office, (3 items) (Box-folder 9:7)
  - 2005-2006 F Miscellaneous, (16 items) (Box-folder 9:8)
  - 2004-2005 Facilities Management, (2 items) (Box-folder 10:1)
  - 2005 Faculty, (1 item) (Box-folder 10:2)
  - 2005-2006 Faculty Forum for Scientific Research, (2 items) (Box-folder 10:3)
  - 2005 Fall Convocation, (57 items) (Box-folder 10:4)
  - 2005-2006 Federal Relations, (20 items) (Box-folder 10:5)
  - 2005-2006 Finance, Vice President of, (22 items) (Box-folder 10:6)
  - 2005-2006 Financial Aid, (6 items) (Box-folder 10:7)
  - 2005-2006 G Miscellaneous, (5 items) (Box-folder 10:8)
  - 2005 General Assembly, (3 items) (Box-folder 10:9)
  - 2006 General Assembly, (5 items) (Box-folder 11:1)
  - 2005 Governmental Relations, (10 items) (Box-folder 11:2)
  - 2006 Governmental Relations, (10 items) (Box-folder 11:3)
  - 2005 Governor's Office, (19 items) (Box-folder 11:4)
  - 2006 Governor's Office, (19 items) (Box-folder 11:5)
  - 2005-2006 H Miscellaneous, (26 items) (Box-folder 12:1)
  - 2006 Honor Committee, (4 items) (Box-folder 12:2)
  - 2005-2006 Human Resources, (6 items) (Box-folder 12:3)
  - 2005-2006 Hurricane Katrina, (4 items) (Box-folder 12:4)
  - 2005-2006 I Miscellaneous, (11 items) (Box-folder 12:5)
  - 2005-2006 Institutional Assessment and Studies, (6 items) (Box-folder 12:6)
  - 2005-2006 International Studies, (12 items) (Box-folder 12:7)
  - 2005-2006 Invitations to Inaugurations, (23 items) (Box-folder 12:8)
  - 2005 Ivy Foundation, (10 items) (Box-folder 13:1)
  - 2005-2006 J Miscellaneous, (12 items) (Box-folder 13:2)
  - 2005-2006 Jefferson Foundation, (4 items) (Box-folder 13:3)
  - 2003-2006 Jefferson Park Avenue Project, (17 items) (Box-folder 13:4)
  - 2005-2006 Jefferson Scholars Foundation, (10 items) (Box-folder 13:5)
  - 2005-2006 K Miscellaneous, (15 items) (Box-folder 13:6)
  - 2005-2006 L Miscellaneous, (19 items) (Box-folder 13:7)
  - 2005-2006 Law School, (11 items) (Box-folder 13:8)
  - 2005-2006 Library, (6 items) (Box-folder 13:9)
  - 2005-2006 Ma-Mel Miscellaneous, (26 items) (Box-folder 14:1)
  - 2005-2006 Mem-Mz Miscellaneous, (11 items) (Box-folder 14:2)
  - 2005 Management and Budget, Office of, (12 items) (Box-folder 14:3)
  - 2006 Management and Budget, Office of, (7 items) (Box-folder 14:4)
  - 2005 August-September Mariners' Museum Board of Trustees, (6 items) (Box-folder 14:5)
  - 2005 December Mariners' Museum Board of Trustees, (8 items) (Box-folder 14:6)
  - 2006 Mariners' Museum Board of Trustees, (7 items) (Box-folder 14:7)
  - 2005-2006 Medical Center, (8 items) (Box-folder 14:8)
  - 2006 Medical Center-Medical School, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:9)
  - 2006 Medical Center-Nursing School, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:10)
  - 2005-2006 Na-Nd Miscellaneous, (10 items) (Box-folder 15:1)
  - 2005-2006 Ne-Nz Miscellaneous, (21 items) (Box-folder 15:2)
  - 2005-2006 National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges, (5 items) (Box-folder 15:3)
  - 2005-2006 O Miscellaneous, (5 items) (Box-folder 15:4)
  - 2005-2006 Pa-Pm Miscellaneous, (16 items) (Box-folder 15:5)
  - 2005-2006 Po-Pz Miscellaneous, (12 items) (Box-folder 15:6)
  - 2005-2006 Planning, (3 items) (Box-folder 15:7)
  - 2005-2006 Politics, (5 items) (Box-folder 15:8)
  - 2005-2006 President's Cabinet, (8 items) (Box-folder 15:9)
  - 2005-2006 Procurement Services, (2 items) (Box-folder 15:10)
  - 2006 February-June Provost, (16 items) (Box-folder 15:11)
  - 2005 June-August Provost Task Force on Public Policy, (8 items) (Box-folder 16:1)
  - 2005 September-2006 January Provost Task Force on Public Policy, (19 items) (Box-folder 16:2)
  - 2005-2006 Ra-Rg Miscellaneous, (9 items) (Box-folder 16:3)
  - 2005-2006 Rh-Rz Miscellaneous, (9 items) (Box-folder 16:4)
  - 2005 Registrar, (2 items) (Box-folder 16:5)
  - 2005-2006 Research, Vice President of, (7 items) (Box-folder 16:6)
  - 2005 ROTC, (2 items) (Box-folder 16:7)
  - 2005-2006 Sa-Sh Miscellaneous, (13 items) (Box-folder 16:8)
  - 2005 Si Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 16:9)
  - 2005-2006 Sl-Sm Miscellaenous, (7 items) (Box-folder 17:1)
  - 2005-2006 So-Sz Miscellaenous, (11 items) (Box-folder 17:2)
  - 2005-2006 Semester at Sea, (25 items) (Box-folder 17:3)
  - 2005-2006 Senate Faculty, (5 items) (Box-folder 17:4)
  - 2005-2006 Society of University Families, (7 items) (Box-folder 17:5)
  - 2005-2006 Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, (6 items) (Box-folder 17:6)
  - 2005-2006 South Lawn Project, (9 items) (Box-folder 17:7)
  - 2006 April Sponsored Programs, Office of, (3 items) (Box-folder 18:1)
  - 2005 July-September State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, (8 items) (Box-folder 18:2)
  - 2005 September-2006 June State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, (9 items) (Box-folder 18:3)
  - 2005 April-November Student Affairs, (16 items) (Box-folder 18:4)
  - 2005 December-2006 June Student Affairs, (19 items) (Box-folder 18:5)
  - 2006 Student Affairs-Fraternities and Sororities, (3 items) (Box-folder 18:6)
  - 2005 Student Council, (1 item) (Box-folder 18:7)
  - 2005-2006 Summer Session, (3 items) (Box-folder 18:8)
  - 2005-2006 Ta-Tn Miscellaneous, (5 items) (Box-folder 19:1)
  - 2005-2006 To-Tz Miscellaneous, (16 items) (Box-folder 19:2)
  - 2005 Thomas, Clayton A., Jr., (1 item) (Box-folder 19:3)
  - 2005-2006 U Miscellaneous, (8 items) (Box-folder 19:4)
  - 2004-2006 United States Department of Education, (11 items) (Box-folder 19:5)
  - 2005-2006 University Relations, (12 items) (Box-folder 19:6)
  - 2004-2006 University of Virginia's College at Wise, (15 items) (Box-folder 19:7)
  - 2004 University of Virginia Foundation, (1 item) (Box-folder 19:8)
  - 2005 University Press, (2 items) (Box-folder 19:9)
  - 2005-2006 Vi Miscellaneous-Folder 1 of 2, (9 items) (Box-folder 20:1)
  - 2005-2006 Vi Miscellaneous-Folder 2 of 2, (18 items) (Box-folder 20:2)
  - 2005-2006 Valedictory Exercises, (3 items) (Box-folder 20:3)
  - 2004-2005 Vice Presidents' Retreat, (7 items) (Box-folder 20:4)
  - 2005-2006 Wa-Wh Miscellaneous, (13 items) (Box-folder 20:5)
  - 2005-2006 Wi-Wz Miscellaneous, (13 items) (Box-folder 20:6)
  - 2005 Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service, (2 items) (Box-folder 20:7)
  - 2006 Z Miscellaneous, (2 items) (Box-folder 20:8)
- Series II: Restricted Materials
  - 2005 A Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 21:1)
  - 2005 April-September Admissions, (13 items) (Box-folder 21:2)
  - 2005 October-November Admissions, (38 items) (Box-folder 21:3)
  - 2005 December-2006 January Admissions, (39 items) (Box-folder 21:4)
  - 2006 February-March Admissions, (22 items) (Box-folder 21:5)
  - 2006 March-April Admissions, (29 items) (Box-folder 21:6)
  - 2006 April-May Admissions, (23 items) (Box-folder 21:7)
  - 2005 June-2006 February Audit Department, (17 items) (Box-folder 22:1)
  - 2006 March-June Audit Department, (14 items) (Box-folder 22:2)
  - 2005-2006 B Miscellaneous, (13 items) (Box-folder 22:3)
  - 2005-2006 C Miscellaneous, (4 items) (Box-folder 22:4)
  - 2005 Community Relations, (1 item) (Box-folder 22:5)
  - 2005-2006 Condolences, (16 items) (Box-folder 22:6)
  - 2006 D Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 22:7)
  - 2005 Darden School, (4 items) (Box-folder 22:8)
  - 2005 November Deans' Development Forum, (2 items) (Box-folder 22:9)
  - 2005-2006 Development, (2 items) (Box-folder 23:1)
  - 2004 Education School, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:2)
  - 2005 Engineering and Applied Sciences, School of, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:3)
  - 2005-2006 Equal Opportunity Programs, (9 items) (Box-folder 23:4)
  - 2006 F Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:5)
  - 2006 Federal Relations, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:6)
  - 2005-2006 Financial Aid, (6 items) (Box-folder 23:7)
  - 2005-2006 G Miscellaneous, (2 items) (Box-folder 23:8)
  - 2005-2006 Human Resources, (8 items) (Box-folder 23:9)
  - 2005 Institute for Shipboard Education, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:10)
  - 2005 International Studies, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:11)
  - 2005 K Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 23:12)
  - 2005 Law School, (2 items) (Box-folder 24:1)
  - 2005 Management and Budget, Office of, (1 item) (Box-folder 24:2)
  - 2005 Medical Center, (1 item) (Box-folder 24:3)
  - 2006 May N Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 24:4)
  - 2005-2006 P Miscellaneous, (2 items) (Box-folder 24:5)
  - 2006 Procurement Services, (1 item) (Box-folder 24:6)
  - 2005-2006 Provost, (4 items) (Box-folder 24:7)
  - 2005 R-S Miscellaneous, (6 items) (Box-folder 24:8)
  - 2005-2006 Recommendations, (11 items) (Box-folder 24:9)
  - 2005-2006 Student Affairs, (5 items) (Box-folder 24:10)
  - 2006 T Miscellaneous, (1 item) (Box-folder 24:11)
  - 2005 University of Virginia's College at Wise, (1 item) (Box-folder 24:12)